Hello, and welcome back.
大家好 欢迎回来
In this week we're going to go over the basics of neural network programming.
这周我们将学习神经网络的基础知识
It turns out that when you implement a neural network there
需要注意的是 当实现一个神经网络的时候
are some techniques that are going to be really important.
我们需要知道一些非常重要的技术和技巧
For example, if you have a training set of m training examples,
例如 有一个包含m个样本的训练集
you might be used to processing the training set by having a for loop
你很可能习惯于用一个for循环
step through your m training examples.
来遍历训练集中的每个样本
But it turns out that when you're implementing a neural network,
但是 当实现一个神经网络的时候
you usually want to process your entire training set
我们通常不直接使用for循环
without using an explicit for loop to loop over your entire training set.
来遍历整个训练集
So, you'll see how to do that in this week's materials.
所以在这周的课程中 你将学会如何处理训练集
Another idea, when you organize
the computation of, in your network,
另外 在神经网络的计算中
usually you have what's called a
通常先有一个叫做前向传导(forward pass)或
forward pass or forward propagation step,
叫做前向传播(foward propagation)的步骤
followed by a backward pass or
接着有一个叫做反向传导(backward pass)
what's called a backward propagation step.
或叫做反向传播(backward propagation)的步骤
And so in this week's materials, you also get an introduction about why
所以这周 我也会向你介绍为什么
the computations, in learning an neural network can be organized in this forward
神经网络的训练过程可以分为前向传播
propagation and a separate backward propagation.
和反向传播两个独立的部分
For this week's materials I want to convey these ideas using
在课程中 我将使用逻辑回归(logistic regression)来传达这些想法
logistic regression in order to make the ideas easier to understand.
以使大家能够更加容易地理解这些概念
But even if you've seen logistic regression before, I think that there'll
即使你之前了解过逻辑回归 我认为
be some new and interesting ideas for you to pick up in this week's materials.
这里还是有些新的、有趣的东西等着你去发现和了解
So with that, let's get started.
所以 现在开始进入正题
Logistic regression is an algorithm for binary classification.
逻辑回归是一个用于二分类(binary classification)的算法
So let's start by setting up the problem.
首先我们从一个问题开始说起
Here's an example of a binary classification problem.
这里有一个二分类问题的例子
You might have an input of an image, like that, and
假如你有一张图片作为输入 比如这只猫
want to output a label to recognize
this image as being either a cat,
然后 如果识别这张图片为猫 则输出标签1作为结果
in which case you output 1,
or not-cat in which case you output 0,
如果识别出不是猫 那么输出标签0作为结果
and we're going to use y to denote the output label.
现在我们可以用字母y来表示输出的结果标签
Let's look at how an image is represented in a computer.
我们来看看一张图片在计算机中是如何表示的
To store an image your computer stores three separate matrices
为了保存一张图片 需要保存三个矩阵
corresponding to the red, green, and blue color channels of this image.
它们分别对应图片中的红、绿、蓝三种颜色通道
So if your input image is 64 pixels by 64 pixels,
如果你的图片大小为64x64像素
then you would have 3 64 by 64 matrices
那么你就有三个规模为64x64的矩阵
corresponding to the red, green and blue pixel intensity values for your images.
分别对应图片中红、绿、蓝三种像素的强度值
Although to make this little slide I drew these as much smaller matrices, so
为了便于表示 这里我画了三个很小的矩阵
these are actually 5 by 4 matrices rather than 64 by 64.
注意它们的规模为5x4 而不是64x64
So to turn these pixel intensity values into a feature vector, what we're
为了把这些像素值放到一个特征向量中
going to do is unroll all of these pixel values into an input feature vector x.
我们需要把这些像素值提取出来 然后放入一个特征向量x
So to unroll all these pixel intensity values into feature vector, what we're
为了把这些像素值转换为特征向量
going to do is define a feature vector x corresponding to this image as follows.
我们需要像下面这样定义一个特征向量x来表示这张图片
We're just going to take all the pixel values 255, 231, and so on.
我们把所有的像素都取出来 例如255、231等等
255, 231, and so on until we've listed all the red pixels.
255、231等等 直到取完所有的红色像素
And then eventually 255 134 255,134 and so
接着最后是255、134、255、134等等
on until we get a long feature vector listing out all the red,
直到得到一个特征向量 把图片中所有的
green and blue pixel intensity values of this image.
红、绿、蓝像素值都列出来
If this image is a 64 by 64 image, the total dimension
如果图片的大小为64x64像素 那么向量x的总维度
of this vector x will be 64 by 64 by 3 because that's
将是64乘以64乘以3 因为这就是
the total numbers we have in all of these matrixes.
三个像素矩阵中像素的总量
Which in this case, turns out to be 12,288,
在这个例子中 结果为12,288
that's what you get if you multiply all those numbers.
如果你把它们乘起来，这就是你将得到的结果
And so we're going to use nx=12288
现在我们用nx=12288
to represent the dimension of the input features x.
来表示输入特征向量x的维度
And sometimes for brevity, I will also just use lowercase n
有时候为了简洁 我会直接用小写的n
to represent the dimension of this input feature vector.
来表示输入特征向量的维度
So in binary classification, our goal is to learn a classifier that can input
所以 在二分类问题中 我们的目标就是习得一个分类器
an image represented by this feature vector x.
它以图片的特征向量x作为输入
And predict whether the corresponding label y is 1 or 0,
然后预测输出结果y为1还是0
that is, whether this is a cat image or a non-cat image.
也就是预测图片中是否有猫
Let's now lay out some of the notation that we'll
接下来我们说明一些在余下课程中
use throughout the rest of this course.
需要用到的一些符号
A single training example is represented by a pair (x, y),
用一对(x, y)来表示一个单独的样本
where x is an x-dimensional feature vector
x代表x维的特征向量
and y, the label, is either 0 or 1.
y表示标签(输出结果) 只能为0或1
Your training sets will comprise lower-case m training examples.
而训练集将由(小写的)m个训练样本组成
And so your training sets will be written (x(1), y(1)) which is the input and output
其中(x(1), y(1))表示第一个样本的输入和输出
for your first training example (x(2), y(2)) for the second training example
(x(2), y(2)) 表示第二个样本的输入和输出
up to (x(m),y(m)) which is your last training example.
直到最后一个样本(x(m),y(m))
And then that altogether is your entire training set.
然后所有的这些一起表示整个训练集
So I'm going to use lowercase m to denote the number of training samples.
我将使用小写的字母m来表示训练样本的个数
And sometimes to emphasize that this is the number of train examples,
有时候为了强调这是训练样本的个数
I might write this as M = M train.
我会写作M=M下标train
And when we talk about a test set,
当涉及到测试集的时候
we might sometimes use m subscript test to denote the number of test examples.
我们会使用m下标test来表示测试集的样本数
So that's the number of test examples.
所以这是测试集的样本数
Finally, to output all of the training examples into a more compact notation,
最后 为了能把训练集表示得更紧凑一点
we're going to define a matrix, capital X.
我们会定义一个矩阵 用大写的X表示
As defined by taking you training set inputs x1, x2 and
它由输入向量x1、x2等等组成
so on and stacking them in columns.
像这样放在矩阵的列中
So we take x1 and put that as a first column of this matrix,
所以现在 我们把x1作为第一列放在矩阵中
x2, put that as a second column and so on down to xm,
x2作为第二列 直到xm放到第m列
then this is the matrix capital X.
然后我们就得到了训练集矩阵(大写的)X
So this matrix X will have m columns, where m is the number of train
所以这个矩阵有m列 m是训练集的样本数量
examples and the number of railroads, or the height of this matrix is NX.
然后这个矩阵的高度记为nX
Notice that in other causes, you might see the matrix capital
注意 有时候可能因为其他某些原因
X defined by stacking up the train examples in rows like so,
矩阵X会由训练样本按照行堆叠起来 而不是列 例如这样
x1 transpose down to xm transpose.
x1的转置直到xm的转置
It turns out that when you're implementing neural networks using
但是在实现神经网络的时候 使用左边的这种形式
this convention I have on the left, will make the implementation much easier.
会让整个实现的过程变得更加简单
So just to recap, X is a nx by m dimensional matrix, and
现在来简单温习一下 X是一个规模为nx乘以m的矩阵
when you implement this in Python,
当你用Python实现的时候
you see that x.shape, that's the python command for
你会看到x.shape 这是一条Python命令
founding the shape of the matrix, that this an nx, m.
用于设置矩阵的规模 即x.shape等于nx逗号m
That just means it is an nx by m dimensional matrix.
表示X是一个规模为nx乘以m的矩阵
So that's how you group the training examples, input x into matrix.
所以综上 这就是如何将训练样本(输入向量x的集合)表示为一个矩阵
How about the output labels y?
那么输出标签y呢？
It turns out that to make your implementation of a neural network easier,
同样的道理 为了能更加容易地实现一个神经网络
it would be convenient to also stack y in columns.
将y标签放在列中将会使得后续计算非常方便
So we're going to define capital Y to be equal to y1, y2
所以我们定义大写的Y等于y1,y2
up to ym like so.
直到ym
So Y here will be a 1 by m dimensional matrix.
所以Y在这里是一个规模为1乘以m的矩阵
And again, to use the Python notation then the shape of Y will be 1, m.
同样地 使用Python将表示为Y.shape等于1逗号m
Which just means this is a 1 by m matrix.
表示这是一个规模为1乘以m的矩阵
And as you implement your neural network, later in this course, you find that a useful
当你在后面的课程中实现神经网络的时候 你会发现
convention would be to take the data associated with different training
一个好的符号约定能够将不同训练样本的数据很好地组织起来
examples, and by data I mean either x or y, or other quantities you see later.
而我所说的数据 不仅包括x或者y 还包括之后你会看到的其他的量
But to take the stuff or
将不同的
the data associated with different training examples and
训练样本的数据提取出来
to stack them in different columns, like we've done here for both x and y.
然后就像刚刚我们对x和y所做的那样 将他们堆叠在矩阵的列中
So, that's the notation we we'll use for logistic regression and for
所以 这就是我们之后会在逻辑回归
neural networks networks later in this course.
和神经网络上要用到的符号的说明
If you ever forget what a piece of notation means, like what is m or
如果有时候你忘了这些符号的意思 比如什么是m
what is n or
或者什么是n
what is something else, we've also posted on the course website a notation guide
或者忘了其他一些东西 我们也会在课程的网站上放上符号说明
that you can use to quickly look up
what any particular piece of notation means.
然后你可以快速地查阅每个具体的符号代表什么意思
So with that, let's go on to the next video where we'll start to fetch out
好了 我们接着到下一个视频 在下个视频中
logistic regression using this notation.
我们将以逻辑回归作为开始